前一视频中，我们探讨了多元或多变量线性回归假设的形式
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
In the previous video, we talked about
the form of the hypothesis for linear
前一视频中，我们探讨了多元或多变量线性回归假设的形式
regression with multiple features
or with multiple variables.
在这个视频中，我们将介绍如何设定该假设的参数
In this video, let's talk about how to
fit the parameters of that hypothesis.
特别是，我们会讲解如何使用梯度下降法来
In particular let's talk about how
to use gradient descent for linear
处理多元线性回归
regression with multiple features.
快速地总结下我们的变量记号，得到正式的多元线性回归假设
To quickly summarize our notation,
this is our formal hypothesis in
其中，我们已经按惯例，使x0 = 1
multivariable linear regression where
we've adopted the convention that x0=1.
此模型的参数包括从 theta0 到 theta n，但我们不把它看作
The parameters of this model are theta0
through theta n, but instead of thinking
这 n 个独立有效的参数。而是考虑
of this as n separate parameters, which
is valid, I'm instead going to think of
把这些theta参数作为一个 n + 1 维的向量。
the parameters as theta where theta
here is a n+1-dimensional vector.
所以，我只会把此模型的参数看作模型自己的一个向量。
So I'm just going to think of the
parameters of this model
所以，我只会把此模型的参数看作模型自己的一个向量。
as itself being a vector.
我们的成本函数是从 theta0 到 theta n 的J，它通过误差项的
Our cost function is J of theta0 through
theta n which is given by this usual
平方的总和来给定。但又不把 J 看作带n+1个数的函数
sum of square of error term. But again
instead of thinking of J as a function
我会使用更通用的方式把 J 看作是参数为theta向量的函数。
of these n+1 numbers, I'm going to
more commonly write J as just a
所以， theta 在这里还是一个向量。
function of the parameter vector theta
so that theta here is a vector.
这就是梯度下降的样子。我们要不断更新每个theta j 参数，
Here's what gradient descent looks like.
We're going to repeatedly update each
（不是我懒，而是用自然语言来描述数学公式，老是有歧义，具体看视频上显示的公式吧）
parameter theta j according to theta j
minus alpha times this derivative term.
我们再把这写作 theta 的  J，然后 theta j 更新为
And once again we just write this as
J of theta, so theta j is updated as
（不是我懒，而是用自然语言来描述数学公式，老是有歧义，具体看视频上显示的公式吧）
theta j minus the learning rate
alpha times the derivative, a partial
这个求导是成本函数对参数theta j 的求偏导。
derivative of the cost function with
respect to the parameter theta j.
让我们看看这是什么样子时我们实施梯度下降，
Let's see what this looks like when
we implement gradient descent and,
特别是，让我们去看看，偏导数看起来像什么。
in particular, let's go see what that
partial derivative term looks like.
这就是我们使用梯度下降法，并且 N = 1 元时的例子。
Here's what we have for gradient descent
for the case of when we had N=1 feature.
我们有两个独立的更新规则，分别对应参数 theta0 和 theta1
We had two separate update rules for
the parameters theta0 and theta1, and
希望你熟悉这些内容。在这里的这个项，当然就是
hopefully these look familiar to you.
And this term here was of course the
成本函数 对参数 theta0 求的偏导，
partial derivative of the cost function
with respect to the parameter of theta0,
同样地，我们还有一个不同的参数 theta1 的更新规则。
and similarly we had a different
update rule for the parameter theta1.
有一个小小的区别，我们以前只有一元特征值
There's one little difference which is
that when we previously had only one
我们可以把它叫做x(i)，但现在在我们的新的记号表示法中
feature, we would call that feature x(i)
but now in our new notation
我们自然而然把他们称之为（看视频），以表示一个特征值。
we would of course call this
x(i)1 to denote our one feature.
所以在我们只有一个特征值的情况下，就是这样。
So that was for when
we had only one feature.
让我们看看新的算法，我们有多于一个的特征值，
Let's look at the new algorithm for
we have more than one feature,
特征值个数 n 可能比 1 大得多。
where the number of features n
may be much larger than one.
我们得到这个的梯度下降法更新规则，也许对于你们当中，
We get this update rule for gradient
descent and, maybe for those of you that
会微积分的人来说，如果你根据成本函数的定义，然后
know calculus, if you take the
definition of the cost function and take
计算 成本 函数J 对参数 theta j 的偏导，
the partial derivative of the cost
function J with respect to the parameter
你就会发现，这偏导值就是
theta j, you'll find that that partial
derivative is exactly that term that
我在它周围画上蓝框的项。
I've drawn the blue box around.
如果你这样做了，你就得到梯度下降法的具体实现，
And if you implement this you will
get a working implementation of
用于多元线性回归
gradient descent for
multivariate linear regression.
在此幻灯片中，我想做的最后一件事，就是告诉你
The last thing I want to do on
this slide is give you a sense of
为何这些或新或旧的算法是同一类事件，或为何他们
why these new and old algorithms are
sort of the same thing or why they're
是类似的算法，以及为何他们都是梯度下降算法。
both similar algorithms or why they're
both gradient descent algorithms.
让我们来看个例子，现在有两个特征值，
Let's consider a case
where we have two features
或者超过两个的特征值，因此，我们有三条更新规则
or maybe more than two features,
so we have three update rules for
来计算参数 theta0 到 theta2 ，可能其他的 theta值也一样。
the parameters theta0, theta1, theta2
and maybe other values of theta as well.
如果你观察theta0的更新规则，你会发现，
If you look at the update rule for
theta0, what you find is that this
这更新规则和我们以前用过的更新规则一样
update rule here is the same as
the update rule that we had previously
以前那个 n = 1 的例子的更新规则。
for the case of n = 1.
当然，它们等效的原因是
And the reason that they are
equivalent is, of course,
因为在我们符号惯例中，我们有 x (i) 0 = 1 的约定，
because in our notational convention we
had this x(i)0 = 1 convention, which is
这就是为什么洋红色框里左右两边会等效。
why these two term that I've drawn the
magenta boxes around are equivalent.
同样地，如果你注意到 theta1 的更新规则，你会发现
Similarly, if you look the update
rule for theta1, you find that
这一项等效于我们以前用过的项
this term here is equivalent to
the term we previously had,
或者说方程，或更新规则，我们曾用于以前的 theta1
or the equation or the update
rule we previously had for theta1,
当然我们只是使用了这种新的符号 x (i) 1 来表示
where of course we're just using
this new notation x(i)1 to denote
我们第一元特征值，现在，我们有多个特征值，
our first feature, and now that we have
more than one feature we can have
于是我们有相似的更新规则，用于诸如 theta2 等参数。
similar update rules for the other
parameters like theta2 and so on.
此幻灯片中还有很多内容，所以我无比明确地鼓励你
There's a lot going on on this slide
so I definitely encourage you
去暂停视频，一丝不苟地观看这张幻灯片上的数学内容
if you need to to pause the video
and look at all the math on this slide
以确保您掌握了这上面的一切。
slowly to make sure you understand
everything that's going on here.
但是，如果你实现了写在这里的算法，
But if you implement the algorithm
written up here then you have
那么你就已经拥有一个多元线性回归的具体实现。
a working implementation of linear
regression with multiple features.